Dan Rosen

SUMMARY

Technical leader with over 15 years of experience in software engineering, management, training and coaching. Recently transplanted back to Boston, and looking to tackle some substantive new engineering problems. Above all, I hope to be part of a team that values learning and collaboration, where I can share my knowledge and learn from my teammates.

SKILLS

Scala: Finagle, Akka, Spray, ScalaTest, ScalaCheck, Scalaz, Shapeless, SBT

Java: Guice, Jersey, Jackson, JUnit, Hamcrest, Mockito, Maven

Other languages: JavaScript (Node.js), Haskell, C/C++

Environments and tools: AWS (Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda), Docker, Mesos, MySQL, Cassandra

CAREER

The Post-Twitter Career Doldrums · Greater Boston Area, MA

2016 - Present

11.2015 - 04.2016 (the good part): Got married, traveled and resettled in the Boston area to be closer to family. 09.2016 - 12.2016: Engineering Manager at Fitbit. Ran a "critical" yet unstaffed initiative; downhill from there. 03.2017 - Present: Principal Engineer at Cimpress. I mostly provide technical support for half-built products.

Twitter · Tech Lead / Engineering Manager. San Francisco, CA

04.2013 - 10.2015

Managed three teams responsible for Twitter's REST API, including auth, rate-limiting and Scala frameworks. Led API monolith decomposition and Mesos migration to improve fault tolerance and developer productivity. Implemented API reliability and performance dashboards, used as a template for all new services.

Fixed sporadic authentication outages by porting from MySQL to "Manhattan" (homegrown Cassandra clone).

Developed "Scala School" course and taught to all engineers in new-hire onboarding.

 $Provided \ 1:1 \ coaching \ and \ performance \ management \ for \ 10 \ engineers \ ranging \ from \ in terms \ to \ senior \ staff.$

Mentored three aspiring junior engineers at Hackbright, a local developer bootcamp for women.

Marakana · Lead Instructor. San Francisco, CA

11.2011 - 04.2013

Taught and coached over 1,000 engineers in person and via LiveLessons (published by Addison-Wesley).

 $Researched, developed \ and \ delivered \ new \ training \ courses \ on \ Scala, Hadoop \ and \ JAX-RS.$

Modernized Marakana's Java courses, including fundamentals, advanced concurrency and web development.

Community events: organized the SF Scala meetup, and production of NEScala 2012 conference videos.

Business development: spearheaded Scala training partnership with Typesafe (now Lightbend).

Atlassian · Senior Software Engineer. San Francisco, CA

03.2010 - 08.2011

Maintained cross-product plugin SDK and built the "Developer" tab in the Universal Plugin Manager.

Designed and built plugin usage tracking dashboard for the Atlassian Plugin Exchange (now Marketplace).

Wrote plugin development tutorials, documentation, presentations and blogs.

Coverity · Senior Software Engineer / Sales Engineer. San Francisco, CA

09.2006 - 04.2009

Developed fast virtual function call resolution and checkers for static defect detection in C++ COM code. Designed and delivered Visual Studio and Eclipse IDE plugins, directing a team of offshore developers. Planned and executed technical strategy for major customers, closing over \$1.5 million in product sales. Led training sessions on software quality, static analysis theory, reporting accuracy and other topics.

ANCIENT HISTORY Cloudmark · Software Engineer. San Francisco, CA

AOL Music · Technical Lead. San Francisco, CA

DoCoMo USA Laboratories · Research Engineer (Contract). San Jose, CA

Netscape Communications / AOL · Software Engineer. Mountain View, CA

08.2004 - 12.2005

02.2003 - 12.2002

04.2002 - 12.2002

07.2000 - 09.2001

EDUCATION

Brown University · Providence, RI

09.1996 - 05.2000

Awarded Bachelor of Arts with Honors in Computer Science, May 2000.

Received Senior Prize in Computer Science, funded by the William Gaston Premium Scholarship. Received Honors in Computer Science for thesis work, "Topics in Markup and Software Engineering."